Blake Rochelle

UXC UX Designer

Contact

Address

Panama City, FL, 32401

Phone

(256) 404-1521

E-mail

blakerochelle@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/blakerochelle/

Skills

Iterative Development

Excellent

UI Prototyping

Very Good

Responsive Design

Excellent

HTML SCSS Javascript
JQuery

Excellent

User Interface (UI) design

Very Good

Web application development

Very Good

Highly skilled UX designer and front-end web developer with 15 years experience in designing and integrating new website functionality and prototyping interactive product application interfaces. Designed a consumer web rater that increased annual direct sales by \$650,000 per year and a user research tool that cut research time in half, significantly reduced risk and improved annual revenue loss by ~\$250,000.

Work History

2010-09 -Current

UX Designer

Kemper Corporation, Previously Infinity Insurance, Birmingham, AL

- Lead UX designer for Infinity Insurance
- Promoted and ensured consistent look, feel and experience across multiple Kemper/Infinity domains and platforms.
- Defined user experience concepts and provided design layouts, workflows, prototypes and high-fidelity graphics.
- Created and maintained libraries of reusable web components.
- Closely collaborated with cross-functional teams and business units to turn requirements into completed apps, within project deadlines, and to identify and quickly address problems.
- Developed and facilitated UX workshops, to help promote optimum user experience across the organization, with 95% positive feedback from attendees.

2003-10 -2010-09

Lead Web Developer

Red Mountain Technologies, Birmingham, AL

- Utilized user-centric principals to design and develop web-based applications.
- Maintained existing applications to ensure their accuracy and currency.
- Performed technical support duties and customer interaction training.
- Served as project coordinator which included managing current project goals as well as long term team goals.

 Planned, designed and prepared company newsletter for digital and print dissemination.

2002-02 -2003-10

Customer Service Representative

AutoCheck Auctions, Birmingham, AL

- Vehicle history data provider to over 95% of the auction industry.
- Interacted one-on-one with customers to help serve their individual needs.
- Coordinated with management to strengthen relationships with our customers.
- Analyzed various data streams to determine the accuracy of historical vehicle information.

Education

1997-09 -2001-12 Bachelor of Science: Business Administration, Management Information Systems

Auburn University - Auburn, AL

Certifications

2018-03

UX Certification, Nielsen Norman Group